<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<conf_file>
  <temp_table_ref src="nss_M162/counters/msc/TBSCTC_ext.xml" />
  <kpi name="msc_1338a">
    <formula>
	tbsctc_ext.bscrnc_cc_group1_tcid_1+tbsctc_ext.bscrnc_cc_group1_tcid_2
	</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title><![CDATA[2G Call attempts per BSC terminating in CC Group1]]></title>
      <use><![CDATA[Number of call attempts per BSC terminating in CC Group1. Originating and terminating calls in the measured BSC are counted.]]></use>

<use_experience><![CDATA[ 
<br>Tcat_IDs:
<br>1 => ORIG
<br>2 => TERM
<br>
<br>Note1: With selected Tcat_IDs (ORIG+TERM) all 2G call attempts terminated in CC GROUP1 are counted. 
<br>
<br>Note2: To measure call attempts terminated in CC GROUP1 for each individual traffic category, please consider the following Tcat_IDs:
<br>           
<br>           ->   &quot;2G Originating call attempts per BSC terminating in CC Group1&quot; => Tcat_ID: 1 (ORIG)
<br>           ->   &quot;2G Originating VOICE call attempts per BSC terminating in CC Group1&quot; => Tcat_ID: 9 (VOICE ORIG)
<br>           ->   &quot;2G Originating DATA call attempts per BSC terminating in CC Group1&quot; => Tcat_ID: 13 (DATA ORIG)
<br>
<br>           ->   &quot;2G Terminating call attempts per BSC terminating in CC Group1&quot; => Tcat_ID: 2 (TERM)
<br>           ->   &quot;2G Terminating VOICE call attempts per BSC terminating in CC Group1&quot; => Tcat_ID: 10 (VOICE TERM)
<br>           ->   &quot;2G Terminating DATA call attempts per BSC terminating in CC Group1&quot; => Tcat_ID: 14 (DATA TERM)
<br>
<br>           ->   &quot;2G Incoming terminating call attempts per BSC terminating in CC Group1&quot; Tcat_ID: 4 (INC-TERM)
<br>           ->   &quot;2G Incoming terminating VOICE call attempts per BSC terminating in CC Group1&quot; Tcat_ID: 12 (VOICE INC-TERM)
<br>           ->   &quot;2G Incoming terminating DATA call attempts per BSC terminating in CC Group1&quot; Tcat_ID: 16 (DATA INC-TERM)
<br>
<br>           ->   &quot;2G Originating outgoing call attempts per BSC terminating in CC Group1&quot; Tcat_ID: 3 (ORIG-OUT)
<br>           ->   &quot;2G Originating outgoing VOICE call attempts per BSC terminating in CC Group1&quot; Tcat_ID: 11 (VOICE ORIG-OUT)
<br>           ->   &quot;2G Originating outgoing DATA call attempts per BSC terminating in CC Group1&quot; Tcat_ID: 15 (DATA ORIG-OUT)
<br>
<br>Note3: Clear Codes selection for CC GROUP1 is customer dependent. Here are some examples:
<br>
<br>         - To measure the number of calls terminating due to no answer:
<br>           GROUP1 Clear Codes:
<br>           0006 - B ANSWER TIME OUT
<br>           0007 - CALL WAITING TIME OUT
<br>
<br>         - To measure the number of calls terminating due to call reject:
<br>           GROUP1 Clear codes:
<br>           0206 &#150; CALL REJECTED
<br>           0220 &#150; ANONYMOUS CALLS REJECTION
<br>
<br>         - To measure the number of calls terminating due to early release (before alerting):
<br>           GROUP1 Clear codes:
<br>           030A &#150; CLEAR/A ONHOOK DURING SET-UP PHASE
<br> 
<br>         - To measure the number of calls terminating due to release during alerting:
<br>           GROUP1 Clear codes:
<br>           030B &#150; CLEAR/A ONHOOK DURING WAIT FOR ANSWER PHASE
<br>
<br>PUBLISHED: M14.4
<br>LAST UPDATE: 17-11-2009
<br>THEORETICAL SUMMARY LEVELS: MSC-BSCM;TCAT
<br>
<br>RECOMMENDED SUMMARY LEVELS: MSC-BSCM;TCAT
<br>
<br>KPI CLASS: Traffic
<br>MEASUREMENT(S): Traffic Measurement per BSC/RNC (M399)
<br>
<br>
<br>]]></use_experience>
      <known_problems />
      <open_questions />
      <pm_class />
      <formula>
      	<![CDATA[
<br>SUM(BSCRNC_CC_GROUP1) ;WHERE Tcat_ID = 1,2
<br>
<br>Use AGGREGATED view(s)/table(s)
<br>
<br>Use view(s):
<br>RNS_P_TBSCTC_&lt;Object&gt;_&lt;Time&gt;
		]]>
	  </formula>
      <unit>[#]</unit>
      <tables>XMLNSS_PS_TBSCTC_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
      <history>
        <revision>
          <author><![CDATA[JflxReportGeneratorFromEosflxApp]]></author>
          <date>2009/12/17 15:54:58.682 +0000</date>
          <comment><![CDATA[Source: RSMSC060.xml]]></comment>
        </revision>
      </history>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark />
    <kpi_alias>2G calls term CC Group1</kpi_alias>
    <area_level>all</area_level>
  </kpi>
</conf_file>

