<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<conf_file>
  <info>
    <release number="jflx"/>
    <dst/>
    <implementation/>
    <min_obj_agg/>
    <maxrows>100</maxrows>
    <header>LHO (LTE Handover)</header>
    <csv_title>LHO (LTE Handover)</csv_title>
    <report-description>LTE Handover measurement (M8021) measures handover related procedures irrespective of the LTE network topology (intra eNB and inter eNB Handover) The counters are updated for the source (originating) cell.</report-description>
    <obj_number>20</obj_number>
    <csv_rule>reuse</csv_rule>
    <addon_sorting/>
    <wrap_header>off</wrap_header>
    <help_file>about_kpi_help.htm</help_file>
    <nokia_counter_id_help_file/>
    <nokia_counter_db_help_file/>
    <external_kpi_help_file/>
  </info>
  <column_order>
    <period_duration/>
    <HO_INTFREQ_ATT/>
    <HO_INTFREQ_GAP_ATT/>
    <HO_INTFREQ_SUCC/>
    <HO_INTFREQ_GAP_SUCC/>
    <HO_INTFREQ_FAIL/>
    <HO_INTFREQ_GAP_FAIL/>
    <HO_EMG_PREP/>
    <HO_SB_ATT/>
    <HO_SB_SUCC/>
    <HO_EMG_PREP_FAIL/>
    <HO_EMG_ATT/>
    <HO_EMG_SUCC/>
    <HO_DRX_ATT/>
    <HO_DRX_SUCC/>
    <MRO_LATE_HO/>
    <MRO_EARLY_TYPE1_HO/>
    <MRO_EARLY_TYPE2_HO/>
    <HO_LB_ATT/>
    <HO_LB_SUCC/>
    <HO_PREP_IN_ATT/>
    <HO_PREP_IN_ATT_TC/>
    <HO_PREP_IN_ATT_RR/>
    <HO_PREP_IN_ATT_RL/>
    <HO_PREP_IN_ATT_RO/>
    <HO_PREP_IN_SUCC/>
    <HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_TC/>
    <HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_RR/>
    <HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_RL/>
    <HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_RO/>
    <HO_PREP_IN_FAIL_RAC/>
    <HO_PREP_IN_FAIL_TAC/>
    <period_duration_sum/>
  </column_order>
  <temp_table name="LHO" meas_level="PLMN/RSLTE-MRBTS/RSLTE-LNBTS/RSLTE-LNCEL/RSLTE-MCC/RSLTE-MNC" type="PM" master="yes" pragma="RSLTE" create="yes">
    <koala_meas_id_list>LHO</koala_meas_id_list>
    <counters>
          <counter alias="period_duration" time-alias="period_duration" time-formula="SUM(period_duration)" object-formula="AVG(period_duration)">SUM(period_duration)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_INTFREQ_ATT" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_INTFREQ_ATT)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_INTFREQ_GAP_ATT" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_INTFREQ_GAP_ATT)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_INTFREQ_SUCC" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_INTFREQ_SUCC)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_INTFREQ_GAP_SUCC" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_INTFREQ_GAP_SUCC)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_INTFREQ_FAIL" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_INTFREQ_FAIL)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_INTFREQ_GAP_FAIL" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_INTFREQ_GAP_FAIL)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_EMG_PREP" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_EMG_PREP)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_SB_ATT" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_SB_ATT)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_SB_SUCC" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_SB_SUCC)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_EMG_PREP_FAIL" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_EMG_PREP_FAIL)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_EMG_ATT" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_EMG_ATT)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_EMG_SUCC" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_EMG_SUCC)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_DRX_ATT" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_DRX_ATT)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_DRX_SUCC" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_DRX_SUCC)</counter>
          <counter alias="MRO_LATE_HO" symmetrical="true">SUM(MRO_LATE_HO)</counter>
          <counter alias="MRO_EARLY_TYPE1_HO" symmetrical="true">SUM(MRO_EARLY_TYPE1_HO)</counter>
          <counter alias="MRO_EARLY_TYPE2_HO" symmetrical="true">SUM(MRO_EARLY_TYPE2_HO)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_LB_ATT" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_LB_ATT)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_LB_SUCC" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_LB_SUCC)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_PREP_IN_ATT" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_PREP_IN_ATT)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_PREP_IN_ATT_TC" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_PREP_IN_ATT_TC)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_PREP_IN_ATT_RR" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_PREP_IN_ATT_RR)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_PREP_IN_ATT_RL" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_PREP_IN_ATT_RL)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_PREP_IN_ATT_RO" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_PREP_IN_ATT_RO)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_PREP_IN_SUCC" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_PREP_IN_SUCC)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_TC" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_TC)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_RR" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_RR)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_RL" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_RL)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_RO" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_RO)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_PREP_IN_FAIL_RAC" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_PREP_IN_FAIL_RAC)</counter>
          <counter alias="HO_PREP_IN_FAIL_TAC" symmetrical="true">SUM(HO_PREP_IN_FAIL_TAC)</counter>
          <counter alias="period_duration_sum" symmetrical="true">SUM(period_duration_sum)</counter>
    </counters>
    <table_name>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</table_name>
    <alias_name>LHO</alias_name>
    <ui_name>LTE Handover</ui_name>
  </temp_table>
  <kpi name="period_duration">
    <formula>LHO.period_duration</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>period_duration (period_duration)</title>
      <use>Duration of the measurement period in minutes.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula time-formula="SUM(period_duration)">AVG(period_duration)</formula>
      <unit>min</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>period_duration (period_duration)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:2</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_INTFREQ_ATT">
    <formula>LHO.HO_INTFREQ_ATT</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_INTFREQ_ATT (M8021C0)</title>
      <use>The number of intra LTE inter-frequency Handover attempts. It comprises the intra- and inter-eNB. UPDATED: intra-eNB HO: This counter is updated following the transmission of an RRC Connection Reconfiguration message sent by the eNB to the UE, which indicates a Handover Command to the UE in case that this message is sent in response to the preparation of an inter-frequency Intra eNB Handover. inter-eNB HO - via X2: This counter is updated following the reception of an X2AP:HANDOVER REQUEST ACKNOWLEDGE message from the target eNB in case that this message is received in response to the preparation of an inter-frequency Inter eNB Handover. inter-eNB HO - via S1: This counter is updated following the reception of an S1AP:HANDOVER COMMAND message from the MME in case that this message is received in response to the preparation of an inter-frequency Inter eNB Handover.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_INTFREQ_ATT)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_INTFREQ_ATT (M8021C0)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_INTFREQ_GAP_ATT">
    <formula>LHO.HO_INTFREQ_GAP_ATT</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_INTFREQ_GAP_ATT (M8021C1)</title>
      <use>The number of intra LTE inter-frequency Handover attempts when measurement gaps are configured for the UE. It comprises the intra- and inter-eNB Handover scenario. UPDATED: intra-eNB HO: This counter is updated following the transmission of an RRC Connection Reconfiguration message sent by the eNB to the UE, which indicates a Handover Command to the UE in case that this message is sent in response to the preparation of an inter-frequency Intra eNB Handover and when measurement gaps are configured for the UE. inter-eNB HO - via X2: This counter is updated following the reception of an X2AP:HANDOVER REQUEST ACKNOWLEDGE message from the target eNB in case that this message is received in response to the preparation of an inter-frequency Inter eNB Handover and when measurement gaps are configured for the UE. inter-eNB HO - via S1: This counter is updated following the reception of an S1AP:HANDOVER COMMAND message from the MME in case that this message is received in response to the preparation of an inter-frequency Inter eNB Handover and when measurement gaps are configured for the UE.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_INTFREQ_GAP_ATT)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_INTFREQ_GAP_ATT (M8021C1)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_INTFREQ_SUCC">
    <formula>LHO.HO_INTFREQ_SUCC</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_INTFREQ_SUCC (M8021C2)</title>
      <use>The number of successful intra LTE inter-frequency Handover completions. It comprises the intra- and inter-eNB Handover scenario. UPDATED: intra-eNB HO: This counter is updated following the reception of an internal message in case that it is received for an inter-frequency Intra eNB Handover. inter-eNB HO - via X2: This counter is updated following the reception of an X2AP:UE CONTEXT RELEASE message from the target eNB for an inter-frequency Inter eNB Handover. inter-eNB HO - via S1: This counter is updated following the reception of an S1AP:UE CONTEXT RELEASE COMMAND message from the MME with the cause value Radio Network Layer (Successful Handover) in case that this message is received for an inter-frequency Inter eNB Handover.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_INTFREQ_SUCC)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_INTFREQ_SUCC (M8021C2)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_INTFREQ_GAP_SUCC">
    <formula>LHO.HO_INTFREQ_GAP_SUCC</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_INTFREQ_GAP_SUCC (M8021C3)</title>
      <use>The number of successful intra LTE inter-frequency Handover completions when measurement gaps are configured for the UE. It comprises the intra- and inter-eNB Handover scenario. UPDATED: intra-eNB HO: This counter is updated following the reception of an internal message in case that it is received for an inter-frequency Intra eNB Handover when measurement gaps are configured for the UE. inter-eNB HO - via X2: This counter is updated following the reception of an X2AP:UE CONTEXT RELEASE message from the target eNB for an inter-frequency Inter eNB Handover when measurement gaps are configured for the UE. inter-eNB HO - via S1: This counter is updated following the reception of an S1AP:UE CONTEXT RELEASE COMMAND message from the MME with the cause value Radio Network Layer (Successful Handover) in case that this message is received for an inter-frequency Inter eNB Handover when measurement gaps are configured for the UE.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_INTFREQ_GAP_SUCC)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_INTFREQ_GAP_SUCC (M8021C3)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_INTFREQ_FAIL">
    <formula>LHO.HO_INTFREQ_FAIL</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_INTFREQ_FAIL (M8021C4)</title>
      <use>The number of inter-frequency Handover failures UPDATED: intra eNB HO: Expiration of timer THOoverall in case that the timer was started because of an inter-frequency Inter eNB Handover. inter eNB HO- via X2: Expiration of the timer TX2RELOCoverall (3GPP TS36.423) in case that the timer was started because of an inter-frequency Inter eNB Handover. inter eNB HO - via S1: Expiry of the guarding timer TS1RELOCoverall (3GPP TS 36.413) in case that the timer was started because of an inter-frequency Inter eNB Handover.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_INTFREQ_FAIL)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_INTFREQ_FAIL (M8021C4)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_INTFREQ_GAP_FAIL">
    <formula>LHO.HO_INTFREQ_GAP_FAIL</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_INTFREQ_GAP_FAIL (M8021C5)</title>
      <use>The number of inter-frequency Handover failures if measurement gaps were configured for the UE. UPDATED: intra eNB HO: This counter is updated following the expiration of timer THOoverall in case that the timer was started because of an inter-frequency Inter eNB Handover when measurement gaps were configured for the UE. inter eNB HO- via X2: This counter is updated following the expiration of the timer TX2RELOCoverall (3GPP TS36.423) if the timer was started because of an inter-frequency Inter eNB Handover when measurement gaps were configured for the UE. inter eNB HO - via S1: This counter is updated following the expiration of the guarding timer TS1RELOCoverall (3GPP TS 36.413) in case that the timer was started because of an inter-frequency Inter eNB Handover when measurement gaps were configured for the UE .
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_INTFREQ_GAP_FAIL)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_INTFREQ_GAP_FAIL (M8021C5)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_EMG_PREP">
    <formula>LHO.HO_EMG_PREP</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_EMG_PREP (M8021C6)</title>
      <use>The number of Handover preparations for IMS Emergency Sessions. It comprises the intra and inter eNB Handover scenario. UPDATED: intra eNB HO: Internal eNB trigger. At eNB MM receives a list with target cells from RRM and decides to perform an Intra eNB Handover for IMS emergency session. inter eNB HO - via X2: Transmission of the X2AP: HANDOVER REQUEST message (source eNB -&gt; target eNB; 3GPP TS 36.423) in case that this message prepares an Inter eNB Handover for an IMS emergency session. inter eNB HO - via S1: Transmission of the S1AP: HANDOVER REQUIRED message (source eNB -&gt; MME; 3GPP TS 36.413) in case that this message prepares an Inter eNB Handover for an IMS emergency session.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_EMG_PREP)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_EMG_PREP (M8021C6)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_SB_ATT">
    <formula>LHO.HO_SB_ATT</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_SB_ATT (M8021C7)</title>
      <use>This measurement provides the number of service-based handover attempts. It comprises the intra- and inter-eNB handover scenario. Service-based handovers are used to hand over the UEs with ongoing VoLTE services (QCI1) to specific cells. Only service-based handover events with cause "resource optimization handover" (3GPP TS 36.413, 36.423) (or with equivalent eNB-internal cause for resource optimization handovers) are counted. Handover events with radio-related causes ("handover desirable for radio reasons", "time critical handover") are not counted. Load-based handover events are not counted. UPDATED: This counter is updated following the transmission of an RRC Connection Reconfiguration message (sent by the eNB to the UE), which indicates a Handover Command to the UE in case this message is sent because of a service-based handover.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_SB_ATT)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_SB_ATT (M8021C7)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_SB_SUCC">
    <formula>LHO.HO_SB_SUCC</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_SB_SUCC (M8021C8)</title>
      <use>This measurement provides the number of successful service-based handover completions. It comprises the intra- and inter-eNB handover scenario. Service-based handovers are used to hand over the UEs with ongoing VoLTE services (QCI1) to specific cells. Only service-based handover events with cause "resource optimization handover" (3GPP TS 36.413, 36.423) (or with equivalent eNB-internal cause for resource optimization handovers) are counted. Handover events with radio-related causes ("handover desirable for radio reasons", "time critical handover") are not counted. Load-based handover events are not counted. UPDATED: Intra-eNB HO: This counter is updated following the reception of an eNB-internal message in case that this message is received for a successful service-based intra-eNB handover. Inter-eNB HO - via X2: This counter is updated following the reception of an X2AP:UE CONTEXT RELEASE message from the target eNB in case that this message is received for a successful service-based inter-eNB handover. Inter-eNB HO - via S1: This counter is updated following the reception of an S1AP:UE CONTEXT RELEASE COMMAND message from the MME with cause value Radio Network Layer (Successful Handover) in case that this message is received for a successful service-based inter-eNB handover.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_SB_SUCC)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_SB_SUCC (M8021C8)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_EMG_PREP_FAIL">
    <formula>LHO.HO_EMG_PREP_FAIL</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_EMG_PREP_FAIL (M8021C9)</title>
      <use>The number of failed Handover preparations for IMS Emergency Sessions. It comprises the intra and inter eNB Handover scenario. UPDATED: intra eNB HO: eNB MM receives a list with target cells from RRM. MM or RRM decides not to execute an Intra eNB Handover for any reason. Inter eNB HO via X2: Trigger Event: - Expiry of the guarding timer TX2RELOCprep in case that the timer was started because of transmission of the X2AP: HANDOVER REQUEST message (source eNB -&gt; target eNB; 3GPP TS 36.423) for the preparation of an Inter eNB Handover for an IMS emergency session. or - Reception of the X2AP: HANDOVER PREPARATION FAILURE message from target eNB in case that this meessage is received in response to the preparation of an Inter eNB Handover for an IMS emergency session. Inter eNB HO via S1: Trigger Event: Expiry of the guarding timer TS1RELOCprep (3GPP TS 36.413) in case that the timer was started because of the preparation of an Inter eNB Handover for an IMS emergency session; or Reception of the S1AP: HANDOVER PREPARATION FAILURE message (source eNB &lt;- MME; 3GPP TS 36.413) in case that this message is received in response to the preparation of an Inter eNB Handover for an IMS emergency session.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_EMG_PREP_FAIL)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_EMG_PREP_FAIL (M8021C9)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_EMG_ATT">
    <formula>LHO.HO_EMG_ATT</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_EMG_ATT (M8021C12)</title>
      <use>The number of Handover attempts for IMS Emergency Sessions. It comprises the intra- and inter-eNB Handover scenario. UPDATED: Intra-eNB HO: Trigger Event: Transmission of an RRC:RRCConnectionReconfiguration message (source eNB -&gt; UE; 3GPP TS 36.331) in case that this message is transmitted to command an Intra-eNB Handover for an IMS emergency session. Inter-eNB HO via X2: Trigger Event: Reception of the X2AP:HANDOVER REQUEST ACKNOWLEDGE message (source eNB &lt;- target eNB; 3GPP TS 36.423) in case that this message is received in response to the preparation of an Inter-eNB Handover for an IMS emergency session. Inter-eNB HO via S1: Trigger Event: Reception of the S1AP:HANDOVER COMMAND message (source eNB &lt;- MME; 3GPP TS 36.413) in case that this message is received in response to the preparation of an Inter-eNB Handover for an IMS emergency session.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_EMG_ATT)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_EMG_ATT (M8021C12)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_EMG_SUCC">
    <formula>LHO.HO_EMG_SUCC</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_EMG_SUCC (M8021C15)</title>
      <use>The number of successful Handover completions for IMS Emergency Sessions. It comprises the intra and inter eNB Handover scenario. UPDATED: Intra eNB HO: Trigger Event: eNB-internal message in case that this message indicates a successful Intra eNB Handover for an IMS emergency session. Inter eNB HO via X2: Trigger Event: Reception of the X2AP: UE CONTEXT RELEASE message (source eNB &lt;- target eNB; 3GPP TS 36.423) in case that this message is received because of a successful Inter eNB Handover for an IMS emergency session. Inter eNB HO via S1: Trigger Event: Reception of the S1AP: UE CONTEXT RELEASE COMMAND message (source eNB &lt;- MME; 3GPP TS 36.413) with cause value Radio Network Layer (Successful Handover) in case that this message is received for an Inter eNB Handover for an IMS emergency session.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_EMG_SUCC)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_EMG_SUCC (M8021C15)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_DRX_ATT">
    <formula>LHO.HO_DRX_ATT</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_DRX_ATT (M8021C18)</title>
      <use>This measurement provides the number of Handover attempts for UEs running in DRX mode. UPDATED: Intra-eNB HO: Trigger Event: Transmission of an RRC:RRCConnectionReconfiguration message (source eNB -&gt; UE; 3GPP TS 36.331) in case that this message is transmitted to command an Intra-eNB Handover for UEs running in DRX mode. or Inter-eNB HO via X2: Trigger Event: Reception of the X2AP:HANDOVER REQUEST ACKNOWLEDGE message (source eNB &lt;- target eNB; 3GPP TS 36.423) in case that this message is received in response to the preparation of an Inter-eNB Handover for UEs running in DRX mode. or Inter-eNB HO via S1: Trigger Event: Reception of the S1AP:HANDOVER COMMAND message (source eNB &lt;- MME; 3GPP TS 36.413) in case that this message is received in response to the preparation of an Inter-eNB Handover for UEs running in DRX mode.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_DRX_ATT)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_DRX_ATT (M8021C18)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_DRX_SUCC">
    <formula>LHO.HO_DRX_SUCC</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_DRX_SUCC (M8021C19)</title>
      <use>This measurement provides the number of successful Handover completions for UEs running in DRX mode. UPDATED: Intra eNB HO:Trigger Event: eNB-internal message in case that this message indicates a successful Intra eNB Handover for UEs running in DRX mode. or Inter eNB HO via X2: Trigger Event: Reception of the X2AP: UE CONTEXT RELEASE message (source eNB &lt;- target eNB; 3GPP TS 36.423) in case that this message is received because of a successful Inter eNB Handover for UEs running in DRX mode. or Inter eNB HO via S1:Trigger Event: Reception of the S1AP: UE CONTEXT RELEASE COMMAND message (source eNB &lt;- MME; 3GPP TS 36.413) with cause value Radio Network Layer (Successful Handover) in case that this message is received for UEs running in DRX mode.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_DRX_SUCC)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_DRX_SUCC (M8021C19)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="MRO_LATE_HO">
    <formula>LHO.MRO_LATE_HO</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>MRO_LATE_HO (M8021C20)</title>
      <use>This counter provides the number of Late Handovers. A Late Handover is a sequence of a missed HO attempt (instead of HO: RLF on UE side and optionally recoverable RLF on eNB side) in one cell followed by RRC connection reestablishment request in another cell. UPDATED: Reception of X2AP: RLF INDICATION message satisfying the following conditions: - C-RNTI corresponds to an available UE context - shortMAC-I is included - shortMAC-I matches the local security calculation (successful authentication) - Tstore_UE_cntxt timer associated with corresponding authenticated shortMAC-I is not running source cell: cell receiving the X2AP: RLF INDICATION message is received (source cell of missed HO attempt and optional recoverable RLF on eNB side) Target cell: cell sending X2AP: RLF INDICATION message (cell receiving the reestablishment request after missed HO attempt) The counter is incremented at the source cell. Notes: The case of reestablishment cause 'ReconfigFailure' is excluded from counting. The case of reestablishment cause 'HOfailure' is excluded from counting when re-establishment target cell is prepared for incoming HO, as this means HO has been attempted, not missed. In case of reestablishment request to cell prepared for incoming HO, the case of received PCI different from source cell PCI of prepared HO is excluded from counting. In the source cell of missed HO attempt, a HO preparation for the considered UE context may be ongoing. The target cell of such HO preparation can be different from the cell receiving the reestablishment request.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(MRO_LATE_HO)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>MRO_LATE_HO (M8021C20)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="MRO_EARLY_TYPE1_HO">
    <formula>LHO.MRO_EARLY_TYPE1_HO</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>MRO_EARLY_TYPE1_HO (M8021C21)</title>
      <use>This counter provides the number of Early Handover Type 1. An Early Handover Type 1 is a sequence of a failed HO attempt followed by RRC connection reestablishment in the HO source cell. UPDATED: Reception of RRCConnectionReestablishmentRequest satisfying the following conditions: - reestablishment cause is equal to 'HOfailure' - C-RNTI corresponds to an available UE context for which outgoing HO preparation is ongoing - shortMAC-I is included - shortMAC-I matches the local security calculation (successful authentication) source cell: cell receiving the reestablishment request (source cell of failed HO attempt) target cell: target cell of failed HO attempt The counter is incremented at the source cell. Note: The RRCConnectionReestablishmentRequest after a failed HO is recognized by reestablishment cause 'HOfailure'.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(MRO_EARLY_TYPE1_HO)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>MRO_EARLY_TYPE1_HO (M8021C21)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="MRO_EARLY_TYPE2_HO">
    <formula>LHO.MRO_EARLY_TYPE2_HO</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>MRO_EARLY_TYPE2_HO (M8021C22)</title>
      <use>This counter provides the number of Early Handover Type 2. An Early Handover Type 2 is recognized in the following cases: Case 1: An Early Handover Type 2 is a sequence of a successful connection establishment in HO target cell (attempted HO completed) followed by RRC connection reestablishment in another cell a short time after 'HO completion'. Case 2: An Early Handover Type 2 is a sequence of a successful random access in HO target followed by failed Msg3 reception (attempted HO not completed) followed by reestablishment request in another cell. UPDATED: Reception of X2AP:HANDOVER REPORT message with Handover Report Type ='HO too early'. source cell: cell receiving the X2AP:HANDOVER REPORT message (source cell of attempted HO) target cell: cell sending the X2AP:HANDOVER REPORT message (target cell of attempted HO) The counter is incremented at the source cell. Notes: 'short time' is defined as time period no longer than expiration value of Tstore_UE_cntxt timer up from HO completion. For the sequence of Case2 the reestablishment request (cause 'HOfailure') received at cell prepared for incoming HO or at HO source cell is excluded from counting.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(MRO_EARLY_TYPE2_HO)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>MRO_EARLY_TYPE2_HO (M8021C22)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_LB_ATT">
    <formula>LHO.HO_LB_ATT</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_LB_ATT (M8021C23)</title>
      <use>This measurement provides the number of load balancing Handover attempts. It comprises the intra- and inter-eNB Handover scenario. Load balancing handovers are used to shift cell traffic from a high loaded serving cell to neighbor cells. UPDATED: This counter is updated following the transmission of an RRC Connection Reconfiguration message (sent by the eNB to the UE) which indicates a Handover Command to the UE in case this message is sent because of a load balancing handover.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_LB_ATT)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_LB_ATT (M8021C23)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_LB_SUCC">
    <formula>LHO.HO_LB_SUCC</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_LB_SUCC (M8021C24)</title>
      <use>This measurement provides the number of successful load balancing Handover completions. It comprises the intra- and inter-eNB Handover scenario. Load balancing handovers are used to shift cell traffic from a high loaded serving cell to neighbor cells. UPDATED: Intra-eNB HO: This counter is updated following the reception of an eNB-internal message in case that this message is received for a successful load balancing intra-eNB Handover. Inter-eNB HO - via X2: This counter is updated following the reception of an X2AP: UE CONTEXT RELEASE message from the target eNB in case that this message is received for a successful load balancing inter-eNB Handover. Inter-eNB HO - via S1: This counter is updated following the reception of an S1AP: UE CONTEXT RELEASE COMMAND message from the MME with cause value Radio Network Layer (Successful Handover) in case that this message is received for a successful load balancing inter-eNB Handover.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_LB_SUCC)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_LB_SUCC (M8021C24)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_PREP_IN_ATT">
    <formula>LHO.HO_PREP_IN_ATT</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_PREP_IN_ATT (M8021C25)</title>
      <use>This measurement provides the number of incoming handover preparation attempts irrespective of the handover cause. The counter is updated in the handover target cell for which the incoming handover preparation request was received. The counter is not updated in case of an intra-cell handover. The counter is not updated in case of a RLF (Radio Link Failure) triggered incoming handover. Remark: The number of incoming handover preparation attempts might be greater than the sum of successful and failed handover preparations because failure counters are only provided for a subset of failure causes. UPDATED: Intra-eNB HO: This counter is updated following the reception of an eNB-internal message (source cell -&amp;gt; target cell) in case that this message is received for an intra-eNB handover preparation. Inter-eNB HO - via X2: This counter is updated following the reception of an X2AP: HANDOVER REQUEST message (source eNB -&amp;gt; target eNB) in case that this message is received for an inter-eNB handover preparation. Inter-eNB HO - via S1: This counter is updated following the reception of an S1AP: HANDOVER REQUEST message (MME -&amp;gt; target eNB) in case that this message is received for an inter-eNB handover preparation. Inter-RAT HO: This counter is updated following the reception of an S1AP: HANDOVER REQUEST message (MME -&amp;gt; target eNB) in case that this message is received for an inter-RAT handover preparation.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_PREP_IN_ATT)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_PREP_IN_ATT (M8021C25)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_PREP_IN_ATT_TC">
    <formula>LHO.HO_PREP_IN_ATT_TC</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_PREP_IN_ATT_TC (M8021C26)</title>
      <use>This measurement provides the number of incoming handover preparation attempts caused by the handover cause Time Critical Handover. The counter is updated in the handover target cell for which the incoming handover preparation request was received. The counter is not updated in case of an intra-cell handover. The counter is not updated in case of a RLF (Radio Link Failure) triggered incoming handover. UPDATED: Intra-eNB HO: This counter is updated following the reception of an eNB-internal message (source cell -&amp;gt; target cell) in case that this message is received for an intra-eNB handover preparation with handover cause Time Critical Handover. Inter-eNB HO - via X2: This counter is updated following the reception of an X2AP: HANDOVER REQUEST message (source eNB -&amp;gt; target eNB) in case that this message is received for an inter-eNB handover preparation with handover cause Time Critical Handover. Inter-eNB HO - via S1: This counter is updated following the reception of an S1AP: HANDOVER REQUEST message (MME -&amp;gt; target eNB) in case that this message is received for an inter-eNB handover preparation with handover cause Time Critical Handover.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_PREP_IN_ATT_TC)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_PREP_IN_ATT_TC (M8021C26)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_PREP_IN_ATT_RR">
    <formula>LHO.HO_PREP_IN_ATT_RR</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_PREP_IN_ATT_RR (M8021C27)</title>
      <use>This measurement provides the number of incoming handover preparation attempts caused by the handover cause Handover desirable for Radio Reasons. The counter is updated in the handover target cell for which the incoming handover preparation request was received. The counter is not updated in case of an intra-cell handover. The counter is not updated in case of a RLF (Radio Link Failure) triggered incoming handover. UPDATED: Intra-eNB HO: This counter is updated following the reception of an eNB-internal message (source cell -&amp;gt; target cell) in case that this message is received for an intra-eNB handover preparation with handover cause Handover desirable for Radio Reasons. Inter-eNB HO - via X2: This counter is updated following the reception of an X2AP: HANDOVER REQUEST message (source eNB -&amp;gt; target eNB) in case that this message is received for an inter-eNB handover preparation with handover cause Handover desirable for Radio Reasons. Inter-eNB HO - via S1: This counter is updated following the reception of an S1AP: HANDOVER REQUEST message (MME -&amp;gt; target eNB) in case that this message is received for an inter-eNB handover preparation with handover cause Handover desirable for Radio Reasons.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_PREP_IN_ATT_RR)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_PREP_IN_ATT_RR (M8021C27)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_PREP_IN_ATT_RL">
    <formula>LHO.HO_PREP_IN_ATT_RL</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_PREP_IN_ATT_RL (M8021C28)</title>
      <use>This measurement provides the number of incoming handover preparation attempts caused by the handover cause Reduce Load in Serving Cell. The counter is updated in the handover target cell for which the incoming handover preparation request was received. The counter is not updated in case of an intra-cell handover. The counter is not updated in case of a RLF (Radio Link Failure) triggered incoming handover. UPDATED: Intra-eNB HO: This counter is updated following the reception of an eNB-internal message (source cell -&amp;gt; target cell) in case that this message is received for an intra-eNB handover preparation with handover cause Reduce Load in Serving Cell. Inter-eNB HO - via X2: This counter is updated following the reception of an X2AP: HANDOVER REQUEST message (source eNB -&amp;gt; target eNB) in case that this message is received for an inter-eNB handover preparation with handover cause Reduce Load in Serving Cell. Inter-eNB HO - via S1: This counter is updated following the reception of an S1AP: HANDOVER REQUEST message (MME -&amp;gt; target eNB) in case that this message is received for an inter-eNB handover preparation with handover cause Reduce Load in Serving Cell.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_PREP_IN_ATT_RL)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_PREP_IN_ATT_RL (M8021C28)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_PREP_IN_ATT_RO">
    <formula>LHO.HO_PREP_IN_ATT_RO</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_PREP_IN_ATT_RO (M8021C29)</title>
      <use>This measurement provides the number of incoming handover preparation attempts caused by the handover cause Resource Optimization Handover. The counter is updated in the handover target cell for which the incoming handover preparation request was received. The counter is not updated in case of an intra-cell handover. The counter is not updated in case of a RLF (Radio Link Failure) triggered incoming handover. UPDATED: Intra-eNB HO: This counter is updated following the reception of an eNB-internal message (source cell -&amp;gt; target cell) in case that this message is received for an intra-eNB handover preparation with handover cause Resource Optimization Handover. Inter-eNB HO - via X2: This counter is updated following the reception of an X2AP: HANDOVER REQUEST message (source eNB -&amp;gt; target eNB) in case that this message is received for an inter-eNB handover preparation with handover cause Resource Optimization Handover. Inter-eNB HO - via S1: This counter is updated following the reception of an S1AP: HANDOVER REQUEST message (MME -&amp;gt; target eNB) in case that this message is received for an inter-eNB handover preparation with handover cause Resource Optimization Handover.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_PREP_IN_ATT_RO)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_PREP_IN_ATT_RO (M8021C29)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_PREP_IN_SUCC">
    <formula>LHO.HO_PREP_IN_SUCC</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_PREP_IN_SUCC (M8021C30)</title>
      <use>This measurement provides the number of successful incoming handover preparations irrespective of the handover cause. The counter is updated in the handover target cell for which the incoming handover preparation request was received. The counter is not updated in case of an intra-cell handover. The counter is not updated in case of a RLF (Radio Link Failure) triggered incoming handover. UPDATED: Intra-eNB HO: This counter is updated following the transmission of an eNB-internal message (target cell -&amp;gt; source cell) in case that this message is sent for a successful handover preparation. Inter-eNB HO - via X2: This counter is updated following the transmission of an X2AP: HANDOVER REQUEST ACKNOWLEDGE message (target eNB -&amp;gt; source eNB) in case that this message is sent for a successful inter-eNB handover preparation. Inter-eNB HO - via S1: This counter is updated following the transmission of an S1AP: HANDOVER REQUEST ACKNOWLEDGE message (target eNB -&amp;gt; MME) in case that this message is sent for a successful inter-eNB handover preparation. Inter-RAT HO: This counter is updated following the transmission of an S1AP: HANDOVER REQUEST ACKNOWLEDGE message (target eNB -&amp;gt; MME) in case that this message is sent for a successful inter-RAT handover preparation.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_PREP_IN_SUCC)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_PREP_IN_SUCC (M8021C30)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_TC">
    <formula>LHO.HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_TC</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_TC (M8021C31)</title>
      <use>This measurement provides the number of successful incoming handover preparations caused by the handover cause Time Critical Handover. The counter is updated in the handover target cell for which the incoming handover preparation request was received. The counter is not updated in case of an intra-cell handover. The counter is not updated in case of a RLF (Radio Link Failure) triggered incoming handover. UPDATED: Intra-eNB HO: This counter is updated following the transmission of an eNB-internal message (target cell -&amp;gt; source cell) in case that this message is sent for a successful handover preparation with handover cause Time Critical Handover. Inter-eNB HO - via X2: This counter is updated following the transmission of an X2AP: HANDOVER REQUEST ACKNOWLEDGE message (target eNB -&amp;gt; source eNB) in case that this message is sent for a successful inter-eNB handover preparation with handover cause Time Critical Handover. Inter-eNB HO - via S1: This counter is updated following the transmission of an S1AP: HANDOVER REQUEST ACKNOWLEDGE message (target eNB -&amp;gt; MME) in case that this message is sent for a successful inter-eNB handover preparation with handover cause Time Critical Handover.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_TC)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_TC (M8021C31)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_RR">
    <formula>LHO.HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_RR</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_RR (M8021C32)</title>
      <use>This measurement provides the number of successful incoming handover preparations caused by the handover cause Handover desirable for Radio Reasons. The counter is updated in the handover target cell for which the incoming handover preparation request was received. The counter is not updated in case of an intra-cell handover. The counter is not updated in case of a RLF (Radio Link Failure) triggered incoming handover. UPDATED: Intra-eNB HO: This counter is updated following the transmission of an eNB-internal message (target cell -&amp;gt; source cell) in case that this message is sent for a successful handover preparation with handover cause Handover desirable for Radio Reasons. Inter-eNB HO - via X2: This counter is updated following the transmission of an X2AP: HANDOVER REQUEST ACKNOWLEDGE message (target eNB -&amp;gt; source eNB) in case that this message is sent for a successful inter-eNB handover preparation with handover cause Handover desirable for Radio Reasons. Inter-eNB HO - via S1: This counter is updated following the transmission of an S1AP: HANDOVER REQUEST ACKNOWLEDGE message (target eNB -&amp;gt; MME) in case that this message is sent for a successful inter-eNB handover preparation with handover cause Handover desirable for Radio Reasons.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_RR)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_RR (M8021C32)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_RL">
    <formula>LHO.HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_RL</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_RL (M8021C33)</title>
      <use>This measurement provides the number of successful incoming handover preparations caused by the handover cause Reduce Load in Serving Cell. The counter is updated in the handover target cell for which the incoming handover preparation request was received. The counter is not updated in case of an intra-cell handover. The counter is not updated in case of a RLF (Radio Link Failure) triggered incoming handover. UPDATED: Intra-eNB HO: This counter is updated following the transmission of an eNB-internal message (target cell -&amp;gt; source cell) in case that this message is sent for a successful handover preparation with handover cause Reduce Load in Serving Cell. Inter-eNB HO - via X2: This counter is updated following the transmission of an X2AP: HANDOVER REQUEST ACKNOWLEDGE message (target eNB -&amp;gt; source eNB) in case that this message is sent for a successful inter-eNB handover preparation with handover cause Reduce Load in Serving Cell. Inter-eNB HO - via S1: This counter is updated following the transmission of an S1AP: HANDOVER REQUEST ACKNOWLEDGE message (target eNB -&amp;gt; MME) in case that this message is sent for a successful inter-eNB handover preparation with handover cause Reduce Load in Serving Cell.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_RL)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_RL (M8021C33)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_RO">
    <formula>LHO.HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_RO</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_RO (M8021C34)</title>
      <use>This measurement provides the number of successful incoming handover preparations caused by the handover cause Resource Optimization Handover. The counter is updated in the handover target cell for which the incoming handover preparation request was received. The counter is not updated in case of an intra-cell handover. The counter is not updated in case of a RLF (Radio Link Failure) triggered incoming handover. UPDATED: Intra-eNB HO: This counter is updated following the transmission of an eNB-internal message (target cell -&amp;gt; source cell) in case that this message is sent for a successful handover preparation with handover cause Resource Optimization Handover. Inter-eNB HO - via X2: This counter is updated following the transmission of an X2AP: HANDOVER REQUEST ACKNOWLEDGE message (target eNB -&amp;gt; source eNB) in case that this message is sent for a successful inter-eNB handover preparation with handover cause Resource Optimization Handover. Inter-eNB HO - via S1: This counter is updated following the transmission of an S1AP: HANDOVER REQUEST ACKNOWLEDGE message (target eNB -&amp;gt; MME) in case that this message is sent for a successful inter-eNB handover preparation with handover cause Resource Optimization Handover.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_RO)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_PREP_IN_SUCC_RO (M8021C34)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_PREP_IN_FAIL_RAC">
    <formula>LHO.HO_PREP_IN_FAIL_RAC</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_PREP_IN_FAIL_RAC (M8021C35)</title>
      <use>This measurement provides the number of incoming handover preparation failures caused by the missing Radio Resources. The counter is updated in the handover target cell for which the incoming handover preparation request was received. The counter is not updated in case of an intra-cell handover. The counter is not updated in case of a RLF (Radio Link Failure) triggered incoming handover. UPDATED: Intra-eNB HO: This counter is updated following the transmission of an eNB-internal message (target cell -&amp;gt; source cell) in case that this message is sent for a handover preparation failure with failure cause No Radio Resources Available In Target Cell. Inter-eNB HO - via X2: This counter is updated following the transmission of an X2AP: HANDOVER PREPARATION FAILURE message (target eNB -&amp;gt; source eNB) in case that this message is sent for an inter-eNB handover preparation failure with failure cause No Radio Resources Available In Target Cell. Inter-eNB HO - via S1: This counter is updated following the transmission of an S1AP: HANDOVER FAILURE message (target eNB -&amp;gt; MME) in case that this message is sent for an inter-eNB handover preparation failure with failure cause No Radio Resources Available In Target Cell. Inter-RAT HO: This counter is updated following the transmission of an S1AP: HANDOVER FAILURE message (target eNB -&amp;gt; MME) in case that this message is sent for an inter-RAT handover preparation failure with failure cause No Radio Resources Available In Target Cell.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_PREP_IN_FAIL_RAC)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_PREP_IN_FAIL_RAC (M8021C35)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="HO_PREP_IN_FAIL_TAC">
    <formula>LHO.HO_PREP_IN_FAIL_TAC</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>HO_PREP_IN_FAIL_TAC (M8021C36)</title>
      <use>This measurement provides the number of incoming handover preparation failures caused by the missing Transport Resources (Transport Admission Control TAC). The counter is updated in the handover target cell for which the incoming handover preparation request was received. The counter is not updated in case of an intra-cell handover. The counter is not updated in case of a RLF (Radio Link Failure) triggered incoming handover. UPDATED: Intra-eNB HO: This counter is updated following the transmission of an eNB-internal message (target cell -&amp;gt; source cell) in case that this message is sent for a handover preparation failure with failure cause Transport Resources Unavailable. Inter-eNB HO - via X2: This counter is updated following the transmission of an X2AP: HANDOVER PREPARATION FAILURE message (target eNB -&amp;gt; source eNB) in case that this message is sent for an inter-eNB handover preparation failure with failure cause Transport Resources Unavailable. Inter-eNB HO - via S1: This counter is updated following the transmission of an S1AP: HANDOVER FAILURE message (target eNB -&amp;gt; MME) in case that this message is sent for an inter-eNB handover preparation failure with failure cause Transport Resources Unavailable. Inter-RAT HO: This counter is updated following the transmission of an S1AP: HANDOVER FAILURE message (target eNB -&amp;gt; MME) in case that this message is sent for an inter-RAT handover preparation failure with failure cause Transport Resources Unavailable.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(HO_PREP_IN_FAIL_TAC)</formula>
      <unit>#</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>HO_PREP_IN_FAIL_TAC (M8021C36)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
  <kpi name="period_duration_sum">
    <formula>LHO.period_duration_sum</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title>period_duration_sum (period_duration_sum)</title>
      <use>Duration of the measurement period in minutes. Values summed up also in object dimension.
      </use>
      <open_questions/>
      <use_experience/>
      <known_problems/>
      <pm_class/>
      <formula>SUM(period_duration_sum)</formula>
      <unit>min</unit>
      <tables>noklte_ps_lho_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_alias>period_duration_sum (period_duration_sum)</kpi_alias>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark/>
    <area_level/>
  </kpi>
</conf_file>