<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<conf_file>
  <temp_table_ref src="rsran/counters/WBTSMON.xml" />
  <kpi name="M5008C5">
    <formula>(wbtsmon.avg_used_ce_dl_wbts)</formula>
    <kpi_info>
      <title><![CDATA[AVERAGE USED CES FOR DL]]></title>
      <use><![CDATA["The average amount of used CE for DL traffic over the whole measurement period duration, obtained by sampling with predefined sampling period, summing all the samples and dividing by the number of samples  for the measurement period duration.In case of Flexi Rel. 1 HW Counter includes all CCH, DCH, HSDPA and HSUPA used resources. HSUPA used resources includes both the Channel Elements reserved statically after HSUPA enabling and later dynamically allocated Channel Elements for HSUPA users. In case of Flexi Rel. 2 HW includes R99 CEs used by R99 users, CSoHSPA users that are allocated to R99 CE licensed area, dynamic CFs that are allocated for HSUPA and R99 CEs consumed for CCHs. In case of mixed Flexi BTS configuration the counter comprises value for BTS level CE usage according to the above HW dependent description.Note: In Flexi BTS, the number of used CEs can temporarily exceed the licensed capacity when PS radio bearer bit rate is upgraded. UPDATED: The counter is updated over the measurement period. The value of the counter is the average value of all samples."]]></use>
      <use_experience />
      <known_problems />
      <open_questions />
      <pm_class />
      <formula>&lt;br&gt;AVG(AVG_USED_CE_DL_WBTS)</formula>
      <unit>Channel Element</unit>
      <tables>NOKRWW_PS_WBTSMON_{OBJ_AGG}_{TIME_AGG}</tables>
      <history>
        <revision>
          <author><![CDATA[JflxReportGeneratorFromEosflxApp]]></author>
          <date>2011/09/29 19:25:32.629 +0100</date>
          <comment><![CDATA[Source: RSRAN131.xml]]></comment>
        </revision>
      </history>
    </kpi_info>
    <kpi_format>float:0</kpi_format>
    <kpi_mark />
    <kpi_alias><![CDATA[AVERAGE USED CES FOR DL]]></kpi_alias>
    <area_level>all</area_level>
  </kpi>
</conf_file>

